# **Curriculum Vitae**

#### **Andrew Karanja**

P.O BOX 5112-00100

Nairobi, Kenya

andrewkaranja007@gmail.com

+254711261436

linkedin.com/in/andrew-karanja-388316170

https://github.com/AndrewKaranja

Portfolio website- andrewkaranja.netlify.app

## Summary

An eager to learn Informatics and Computer Scientist working towards becoming more skilled and a team player in the technological industry in projects that make the world a better place to live in, for everyone. I Have been coding for the last four years and I am good at full stack development using tools and techniques such as React js, Node js, android java, google cloud, aws cloud just to name a few. This experience has enabled me to build both personal and client projects which can be located either on my GitHub or hosted on the world wide web.

## **Experience**

#### TwoMatches / Software Engineer-Frontend

October 2022-Present, Leander, Texas, United States

- Work as a Frontend software engineer.
- Responsible for designing and coding the webapp's UIs
- Tools and technologies used include React js , Next js ,Figma, Mono repos and Git.

### Population Service International / ChatBot Developer Intern

July 2022-December 2022, Nairobi, Kenya

- •We worked on chatbots that are integrated to Facebook ,whatsapp messenger.
- Responsible for designing, coding and modifying chatbots.
- Chatbots we create are used to provide interactive media on health topics such as contraception and sexual wellness that were served to project all around African and Asian countries.
- Some of the projects worked on include SHIPS(NG,UG,KE),A360 project in Tanzania, and Eswatini wellness chatbot just to name a few
- Tools and technologies used include Machine learning, sentiment analysis, DialogFlow and RapidPro.

#### Kinga Sacco / Web Developer

December 2019-Present, Nairobi, Kenya

- Responsible for designing, coding and modifying websites.
- Currently working as the website's Back-office manager.
- I ensure all features of the website function.
- I also manage and maintain the website's chat and loan calculator.

\_\_\_

# **Projects**

#### 3illboard / Founder- http://3illboard.vercel.app/

January 2022 - Present, Nairobi, Kenya

- 3illboard is a Saas platform that is essentially a marketplace for physical ad spaces such us print billboards, digital billboards, moving ads and so many more.
- The project is built on Firebase-Express-React-Node (FERN) tech stack.
- •The Saas also allows for ad space owners to manage their ad listing by creating bookings, Chatting and sharing designs with clients and showing progress of ads from booking to mounting.

#### **UNDP Accelerator Program**

September 2020 - March 2021, Nairobi, Kenya

- My project was selected to participate in an accelerator program organised by Konza in partnership with UNDP and the UK government in a bid to help solve some of the issues faced in our transport industry.
- The accelerator is an ongoing process with a target of pushing the product to the market by mid next year.

## Konza Technopolis / The Great COVID19 Innovation Challenge

May 2020 - September 2020, Nairobi, Kenya

- I was a semi-finalist in the Great COVID19 Innovation Challenge by Konza Technopolis.
- I participated in the 2-day hackathon organised by the Association of Countrywide hubs and partners (Microsoft, UNDP, Oracle, among others).
- I featured in a UNDP article concerning my project, LipaFare, that I worked on during the hackathon. (Linkhttps://www.ke.undp.org/content/kenya/en/home/blog/2020/looking-ahead--how-will-covid-19-shape-the-future-of-work-inken.html).

#### Kenya Children's Homes / Service Based Learning

January 2020 - April 2020, Nairobi, Kenya

- I became the group leader of the volunteers posted at the homes bakery.
- I baked pastries in the bakery. The pastries fed the children at the home and the surplus sold to earn the home some income.
- Helped in the sale of the pastries we baked at the bakery.
- I also assisted in the cleaning of the bakery and its environs.

#### **Education**

#### **Strathmore University** /BSc informatics and computer science

JULY 2018 - SEPTEMBER 2022, Ole Sangale Road, Nairobi, Kenya

Second Class Upper division Graduate.

#### AWS Academy Graduate / AWS Academy Cloud Foundations

SEPTEMBER 2021 - JANUARY 2022, Online Course

Certification by Amazon Web Services (AWS). Issued Jan 2022

#### Google / Fundamentals of digital marketing certification

JANUARY 2020 - FEBRUARY 2020, Online Course

Certification by Think With Google APAC . Issued Feb 2020 Credential ID 6NF 7Q2 SQR

# eMobilis Institute / Certificate in Mobile Technology and

Entrepreneurship: MIT

JANUARY 2018 - APRIL 2018, Westlands, Nairobi

Main things taught in the program include android development, java programming language and entrepreneurship.

# Mang'u High school / Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education

FEBRUARY 2014 - DECEMBER 2017, Thika

Skills

Javascript-vanilla, React JS, Next js, Node JS.

Java-Android, Data structures and algorithms.

**Amazon Web Services** 

Google Cloud Platform

Firebase-Firestrore

Monorepos

Figma

3d modelling and graphics design with blender and inkscape

 $Tools\,\&\, Technologies: Microsoft\, PowerPoint,\, Microsoft\, Word, excel$ 

**Baking** 

Referees

Robert Githungo

ICT manager PS Kenya/Member of credit committee at Kinga sacco +254 726 125281 rgithungo@pskenya.org

Anthony Kabera,
Manager - Credit,
Prime Bank Ltd,
+254 720 996191
anthony.maina@primebank.co.ke.

John Wanjiku, Senior ChatBot Developer, Population Service International +254 733683043 jwanjiku@psi.org